Madoka just has the worst luck...
...coming down with a cold
right before our family trip.
M-my fever finally broke.
But it's too late now...
I really wanted to go to Fiji.
Please hold down the fort
while we're away for Golden Week.
- The Family
And now I'm stuck here for a whole week.
I don't know if I can survive all alone...
That futon has legs!
Rikukaikuu doko ni ikou
Where to go? The land, sea or sky?
Ahiru no Sora
Kimi o sasoitai na
I wanna invite you to come along
Monogatari wa hajima tterunda
The pages of our story have started to turn
Okubyou kaze mo recycle
If you lose your nerve then recycle it
Mayotteru senaka oshite
And let it push you past hesitation
Give and go! Isogou
Give and go! With the flow
Mogutteita honou ga kaodashite
Instincts that are buried deep will always rear their head again
Kakusenai no sa yume ni mita yume
People can't just hide the dreams they once dreamed of
Tobenai tsubasa demo
Even if these wings can't fly
Bokura wa habataite sora o kanjitai
We want to spread them wide and embrace the sky
Naritai jibun ni naritai
Becoming the people who we want to be
Ima dekinai koto mo ashita wa wakannai ze
You never know, the impossible could be possible tomorrow
Waru agaki shiyou
So let's keep up the struggle
Happy go ducky!
It's... too heavy!
Hey! You're late, Kurumatani.
Differing Enthusiasm
Dude, you lugged that thing all the way here?
Nanao Sports
Good morning!
Whoa, that's a lot of luggage!
Allow me to assist you.
Oh... thank you!
Hey, Nao, these are from my dad.
Wow! So many veggies!
They're fresh from our store.
I didn't realize that your family
ran a grocery store, Yashuara.
Yeah, and Nabe's old man
runs a farm down in Ibaraki.
Here's 20 kilos of rice.
Whoa, incredible!
Okay, then, I know this isn't
much of a thank you, but please...
...take these.
F-for us?
They were our display pieces,
so they're not the cleanest.
Sweet! A perfect fit!
Since basketball puts a
lot of strain on the legs,
I thought you guys should have proper shoes.
I think I want get married to Nao...!
Where are we gonna be sleeping?
And also eat our meals.
You'll all be sleeping in the gym, obviously.
We have permission to use the Home Ec classroom
for cooking and eating.
So then, where will you sleep, Nao?
Mr. Satsuki unlocked the break room for me,
but to be honest...
...I'm scared of sleeping by myself,
so I'll stay with all of you.
WITH ALL OF US?!
This is the best training camp ever!
Okay everybody, get changed
and then meet in the gym!
ROGER!
Yoko:
Did you get over your cold?
I hear the boys' team is doing a training camp right now.
A training camp?
Yoko:
I hear the boys' team is doing a training camp right now.
That sounds like a lot of fun!
I thought that we'd end up
doing intense training all day, but...
This might actually be fun,
like one of those seaside schools!
I brought a console for us to play with.
The Legend of Rails
Nice, Yasu!
I guess we're having a game tourney tonight!
Chiaki's Notes
From what I've uncovered,
Nao's grades in Home Ec are at the top of her class.
Awesome!
I'm looking forward to see
what she cooks us for dinner!
I thought they might get bummed out
at the idea of a training camp,
Yeah, I'm curious to see what it'll be!
but it looks like everyone
will be in good spirits for practice.
Is there anybody who wouldn't be excited
for an event like this?
There's something even more amazing
waiting for us after dinner.
Oh?!
And what makes you say that?
Because I've already worked
my magic on the baths.
You really do have all of
your bases covered, man!
Training camps for the win!
Oh, they're really going at it.
Hey, guys!
I came to hang out!
They're all totally wiped out...
...and there isn't even a ball on the court.
Have they just been running?!
What's going on Nao?
Oh, hello, Madoka.
I heard you guys were doing
a training camp, but...
Yep. We just got started today.
You just started and they're
already this tired?
Yes.
The emphasis of this training is on footwork,
so it's extra difficult for the three newbies.
But for our experienced members,
I'm making them do double what those three are.
The most important thing for them right now
is to build stamina and toughen up.
Running
Time based (20 mins) or Laps outside (30 times)
Stretches
Full court dash
Backwards run
Dash and Stop
Hands up
Jump
Leg Bounce
Shuttle Run
Ladder (20 times x 10 sets)
Y-you're making them do all this in one day?
Skipping
Thigh Lifts
Side Kicks
Leg Bounces
Two Leg Jumps
Slide Steps
Mirror Dribble (zig-zag)
No Ball
Side Step
Cross Step
Dribble Practice
Front back dribble
Left right dribble
High low dribble
2 players  (50 times)
3 players (50 times)
Half 1-on-1 (20 times)
Match Practice
Shooting Practice
We had no morning practice today,
so this was on the easy end.
Sleep
In addition to that, I've set aside
individual practice time for everyone
Sleep | Running/Stretches
Sleep | Running/Stretches | Breakfast
Sleep | Running/Stretches | Breakfast | Morning Practice
Lunch
Lunch | Afternoon Practice
to work on refining their
skills in the evenings.
Sleep | Running/Stretches | Breakfast | Morning Practice
Lunch | Afternoon Practice | Dinner
Lunch | Afternoon Practice | Dinner | Individual Practice
Right now, this is nothing
but a gathering of talented players.
They're still completely
undeveloped as a team.
The entire point of this training camp...
...is to create the real
Kuzu High basketball team.
A team that will survive
the intense competition
of the Kanagawa block and go
to the inter-high tournament.
I believe with all of my heart,
that these guys are capable of that.
I can tell, she's serious about this...
When you've finished with that,
please go and walk it off!
Get your breathing under control
and then start pushing your pace up!
They're like zombies.
But it's hard to believe that until recently,
all these guys did was get into fights.
Hey, Nao?
Is there are anything
that I can help out with?
Huh?
My house is totally empty now,
so I wouldn't mind staying overnight.
Really? That would be a big help!
Um, in that case, I do have
one favor to ask of you.
Sure. Anything you want!
Home Ec. Room
That's a hard pass, even from me.
For real, my stomach
isn't accepting any donations right now.
Those jerks! After all
that effort I put in...
Though I will admit I
screwed up just a little.
Seconds, please. I'm still hungry.
You don't have to force yourself
to eat it on my account.
The hell are you going on about?
It's a little saltier than ordinary,
but it tastes just fine.
Thanks...
And so, the first one bites the dust...
Survival of the fittest.
RIP in peace, Momoharu.
What now? Should we play games or something?
My muscles are so cramped
that I can't move an inch.
Let's just sleep.
Hold your horses, gentlemen.
There's still one thing left...
...the main event of this evening.
Ah, this feels great!
Are you really sure this is okay?
Huh?
Spending your holiday with
us at the training camp.
I have nothing better to do.
This is one good way to pass the time.
Plus, just think, it would be dangerous for you
to be here alone.
Those guys are wild animals.
To be honest, I did have my
own worries about that...
But there's something else.
One more thing I'm really concerned about.
I've amassed a lot of basketball knowledge,
but that's not enough to
make me a proper coach.
I've been putting up a facade of confidence
in front of everyone until now.
But I'm not really sure if what we're doing
will actually work in the end.
Alternatively, I know that
if I seem hesitant at all,
then it will just cause
everyone to have doubts.
I've already prepared myself for the worst
if they end up hating me for it, but...
You're doing just fine. No problem.
I think everyone is already aware
of what they need to do to better themselves.
Plus, I get the feeling that brave face you put on
is getting through to them.
Shhh!
Listen up, I jammed a small rock
into the bottom of this window earlier.
Now it won't fully close
and gets stuck open just a tiny bit.
Your foresight is most admirable, commander!
Great. Then I shall take the first peek!
Whew, I'm feeling refreshed!
Fuji Bathhouse
Sauna
Electric Bath
Whirlpool Jet Bath
It's really nice to have a bathhouse
so close to where the school is.
Wh-what's wrong, Chiaki?!
Ugh, they got me.
What do you mean? Who got you?!
I dunno! Some sort of mysterious creature
that I've never seen before!
Come on! Hurry up, Sora!
Here!
M-Madoka...
Wait up, Madoka...!
You're walking too fast...!
First, a 7.5-kilometer run.
I sure had a nice dream.
Afterwards, an hour of
stretches and loosening up.
Following breakfast, we
get into morning practice.
For the first half of the day,
our practice focuses entirely on footwork.
Greased
Lightning
I'm starting to think he
might not even be human...
Shit! What the hell do we
gotta do to move like he does?
All we've been doing is tripping
up over and over again.
It's because your knees and toes
aren't properly pointed in the same direction.
You can't exert all the power that your legs
are capable of if you're off-balance.
It prevents you from running faster
and stopping more precisely.
If you overpronate or get your
knees pointed the wrong way,
then you have to correct it right away.
When you turn, you should carry your weight
on the ball of your foot.
I think their teamwork will develop nicely
if things keep progressing like this.
Aight, time for another set.
Hold up a sec! Let me rest for a bit!
Cut the crap, you can't be that worn out.
My feet hurt too much to run, dude.
I understand.
Then the two of you can leave the court
and rest for a while.
We can't have anybody pushing so hard
that they break a bone or pass out.
Yeah!
All right!
However!
You will both be required to hold a ball
the entire time you're resting.
I want the three of you, including Yasuhara,
to do that at any time when you're
not actively practicing on the court. Okay?
Whew, I'm super glad that Nanao was the one
who made dinner tonight.
Ow! It's only the second day of our camp,
but my legs are already killing me.
I don't think I'll last for
1,000 shots of practice today.
Kite...
What's up? You here for solo practice, too?
Oh, yeah!
Um, do you want me to throw you some passes?
No need.
You have your own skills that you need
to stay focused on.
Don't spend your time fussing over others.
Work on improving your shot accuracy instead.
I shouldn't fuss over others, huh?
But Kite is the one who spends the most time
fussing over the others during practice.
Dammit! I won't let him outdo me!
I guess it's pretty silly of me
to tell HIM of all people to work on accuracy.
Nope, I'm done! After just 200 shots
I can't even move anymore...
Hey, tell me something.
What do you think about this team?
What do you mean?
Well, the high school that
I was supposed to go to
always recruited top players
from around the country.
"Supposed to go to"?
And the coach there was highly regarded, too.
But despite all of that they've never become
the national champs. Not even once.
When I consider that, I can't help
but wonder why I'm sticking with this team.
The inter-high... is so far from our grasp.
Kite...
Oh, there he is.
Yo Kite! Teach me some
more about how to dribble!
Hey, Yasuhara!
I see you're holding on to the ball
just like Nanao told you to.
Yep.
But I don't get it, is
there a point to all this?
It's so that you develop a
better feel for the ball.
"Better feel"?
Though, I know it can be boring
just fiddling around with it all day like that.
I'll teach you something fun you can do.
Trace the edge of the ball
with your hand, like this.
Then stop it on the back of your hand.
Repeat that in a loop
with both of your hands.
Whoa! Dude, that's awesome!
It's called a "flip."
Whoops!
I can do it, too!
So, hey. I think that you're right.
The inter-high seems like
it's way out of our league right now.
But all we can really do is
keep moving forward, right?
That's a good point.
I guess... everybody starts somewhere.
Man, I wasn't be able to
do the flip at all today.
It takes time, it's not meant to be easy.
What's most important is that you spend
a lot of time handling the ball.
BOYS' BASKETBALL TEAM
And Chiaki goes down again!
Nooooo!
That sucks for you, dude!
Let's reset it.
No way! That's a cheap move, cheater!
Okay, fine then. Let's pick
this up with a clean sla-
You were too tired to run, but it looks like
you've got plenty of energy for games.
Huh?
Didn't our manager give
you an order to hold on
to a ball whenever you're
not out on the court?
You got something to say, punk?
It's called "free" time because we can spend it
doing whatever we want!
That ain't right.
You guys need to double down
and learn all the basics,
so that you can practice with the rest of us.
I can't tell what you guys are thinking,
but I'm dead set on getting
our team to the inter-high.
So please just keep your shit together
and don't hold the rest of us back.
I'm not gonna lie, that kind
of pissed me off just now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Let's not fight guys!
I think you overstepped the
line with that comment, Kite.
It's important to take a
breather sometimes, right?
Come on, just apologize to them.
Why should I?
Everything I said was true and you know it.
Kite!
What do you think?
About what?
Nanao specifically gave
those three something to do.
But only one of them is taking it seriously.
The other two are off playing a game.
Not only that, but they slacked off
during afternoon practice.
But that's...
"Slacked off"?!
Our feet hurt like hell, so
we stopped to get some rest!
Your feet may hurt,
but you could still use your hands.
Why do you think Nanao told you
to keep holding on to the ball?
We have no fucking idea what
the purpose of all this is!
Hey! Please, let's stop this!
Wh-what's going on in here?
BOYS' BASKETBALL TEAM
You need to quit thinking that everyone here
is on the same page about the inter-high.
Those guys have barely started, they're only
at the point where basketball
seems pretty fun.
I know full well what it's like
to fail and be discouraged.
And these are exactly the sort of differences
that drive a wedge into the team.
Not everybody plays the game
just to support somebody else.
I don't want to hear anymore bullshit
about us "holding you back."
Oh, good morning.
You're up early today.
I couldn't really sleep that well.
Because of yesterday?
Yeah.
I don't think anything that
Chiaki said was wrong...
...but even so, I feel the
same way that Kite does.
When it comes to sports, having
a desire to improve becomes
really important the further you go.
I'm sorry.
I should have taken more care
and considered how those two must feel...
Oh, no! It's nothing that
you need to apologize about!
Hey, Tinytown!
It's way too early in the morning
to be going around flirting, dude.
N-nobody around here has
been doing any flirting!
Whatever, have you seen
Nabe or Chucky around?
Huh?
I can't find them anywhere.
All of their luggage is packed up and gone.
They made a break for it.
Hell yeah!
Awesome!
Kick ass!
I'm on fire!
You haven't won yet!
What a haul!
That was genius! Pure genius!
Now THIS is what a vacation should be like!
Screw training camp.
Those guys who want to practice can go right ahead!
That's not fair!
We were the ones who got here first!
What's this? A fight?
That's right! That's right!
You twerps suck, so go find
somewhere else to play.
That's unfair! Cut it out!
Which means I'm willing to spend some time
weeding out the world's bullies.
But mostly because those jerks remind me
of Kite and it's pissing me off.
Hey there, you little punks!
You're too old to be bullying
elementary schoolers.
There's no bullying going on here.
They're the ones who lost
the wager game, fair and square.
"Wager game"?
The basketball hoop in this park
is the only one in the neighborhood.
Whenever there's a debate
about who gets to use it,
both sides settle it with
a wager game of basketball.
And let me guess, you guys were the winners?
Yep. If they want to play, then they should
practice and get good enough to win.
That doesn't seem entirely fair.
I definitely don't agree with the idea that
the better players are
the more important ones.
Hey, listen up, kiddos.
If middle schoolers can
take on elementary kids,
then you have no problem
with high schoolers. Right?
That's fine, but can you
old farts actually play?
Prepare to have your socks knocked off.
And roll out the red carpet!
We're members of the Kuzu
High basketball team!
Let's go out and look for them.
No way. Too much effort, man.
It's better to leave them be.
They're only going to get in our way
if we let them loaf around here.
But that's not...
What did you think?
Huh?
What did you think after you saw them
act like that yesterday?
Well, I...
...but even so, I feel the
same way that Kite does.
Shinshiro Middle
8 points
Kuzu High
Anybody who lacks true
passion for the game won't
get better no matter how much they practice.
You should know that better than anyone else.
Passion...
Are you guys seriously on a basketball team?
You can hardly even dribble
the ball properly!
What the hell? How are
you guys this damn good?
What do you mean?
We've been playing basketball
since first grade.
First grade?
Does that mean these kids have been
playing basketball for more than six years?!
We want to get even better.
We can't afford to spend time playing
with a bunch of little twerps.
So please just keep your shit together
and don't hold the rest of us back.
Basketball is a tough sport,
don't sell it short.
Even if you found those two,
what are you planning to say to them?
"It doesn't matter if you're not motivated,
let's try our best to get
to the inter-high together"?
Or maybe, "who cares about the inter-high,
let's just have fun with it
and play games along the way"?
Well?
No way...
You know I could never
say any of that to them.
I mean, you explained it perfectly earlier.
Those two only think of basketball
as being pretty fun, right?
But that means, it's possible they'll come to enjoy it
even more in the future. Isn't that true?
That's why, they can't just quit playing
because of a minor setback like this.
I've decided. I'm going out
to look for them right now!
Doredake sora o miagetatte
It didn't matter how long you stared up at the sky
Boku wa tobenai to kimi wa itta
You always said that you would never be able to fly
Ato nankai te o nobaseba
One night I cried wondering how long it would take
Todoku no darou to naita yoru
Until I could finally reach you with my hands
Nigedasu koto ni nareteitte
Eventually I got used to just running away
Sore ga yowasa dato shitta ano hi
Until the day I realized that was a weakness
Hajimeyou mata, kyou kara
So let's start it all over, right now
Taisetsu na mono wa itsudemo soba ni atta
The things precious to us were always close at hand
Bokura wa itsumo hitori janai donna toki mo
We are never completely alone at any time in our lives
Toberu sa doko made mo kimi wa
The truth is that you can fly, wherever you want
Dare yori tataku tataku habataite
Spreading your wings to go far higher than anyone else
Nagashita namida no kazu dake
The more tears that you shed
Tsuyoku narunda
Then the stronger you become
Tsubasa hiroge sekai o megutte
Let's use those wings to travel the world over
Dare mo shiranai mirai o sagasou
And find a path to a future that no one knows about
Zutto, zutto, zutto
Always, always, always
Aruite yukou saa, issho ni
Walking onwards, all of us together
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: Towards Victory
Next time: "Towards Victory."